nrl.com 2017-06-23

# National Rugby League Privacy Policy

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy covers the Australian Rugby League Commission Limited, National Rugby League
Limited and each of its associates, related entities and subsidiaries (together, the NRL). For the avoidance
of doubt, a reference in this Policy to the NRL (including the NRL doing or not doing an act) is a reference
to, and is intended to also cover, the Leagues. The NRL recognises that privacy is important and that an
individual has the right to control his or her Personal Information. The NRL is committed to protecting the
privacy of individuals and their Personal Information which the NRL collects during the course of
administering and developing the game of Rugby League.
This Privacy Policy is based on the Australian Privacy Principles in Schedule 1 to the Privacy Act and sets
out the way the NRL handles the Personal Information it collects, uses, discloses and stores on:
(a)      Rugby League participants, including Players and Officials (together, Participants);
(b)      persons who register for any NRL sanctioned accreditation or licensing program;
(c)      persons who purchase or receive information about tickets to Matches, including the NRL, State
         of Origin, National Youth Competitions and Representative Matches;
(d)      persons who subscribe and/or register to any Rugby League membership program, participation
         program, newsletter or promotional offer; or
(e)      persons who request services from the NRL or more information about the NRL, Competitions or
         Matches
         (you, your).
1. ANONYMITY AND PSEUDONYMITY
     Wherever it is lawful and practicable, you will have the option of not identifying yourself, or of using
     a pseudonym, when entering transactions, or otherwise dealing with, the NRL in relation to a
     particular matter.
2. COLLECTION
     2.1       The NRL only collects Personal Information about you by lawful and fair means and as is
               reasonably necessary for one or more of the NRL’s functions or activities in administering
               the game of Rugby League, including for the following primary purposes:
               (a)     organisation, conduct and promotion of Competitions and Matches (including for
                       the purpose of providing information and making ticket offers to you);
               (b)     direct communication with you by Rugby League Administrators;
               (c)     disclosure to Rugby League Partners, unless you have indicated that you do not
                       want to receive any communication from Rugby League Partners;
               (d)     compliance with the NRL Rules, including the administration and development of
                       Rugby League (if you are a Participant); and
                                                                                                              1

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
     (e)      any use that is obvious at the time the Personal Information is collected.
 2.2 Members of the NRL corporate group may also share Personal Information with each other
     for these primary purposes and otherwise in administering and developing the game of
     Rugby League.
 2.3 The types of Personal Information the NRL may collect depends on the purposes for which it
     is collected but may include (without limitation):
     (a)      your name, gender, occupation, residential address, email address, telephone
              number and other contact details;
     (b)      your favourite NRL Club and other information dealings with the NRL or the Clubs
              such as memberships, subscriptions and attendance history at NRL Matches where
              you have used your membership to purchase tickets;
     (c)      purchasing preferences and financial details.
 2.4 Where it is reasonable and practicable to do so, the NRL will only collect your Personal
     Information from you. If you are a Minor, the NRL may collect Personal Information about
     you from your parent or legal guardian.
 2.5 The NRL will collect Personal Information from you mainly through relevant forms (whether
     in hard copy or online) approved by the NRL or the Leagues from time to time. However,
     during the ordinary course of its activities and functions, the NRL may also collect Personal
     Information that is given to it by a third party (such as a corporate partner of the NRL or
     Clubs, or information that is on public record), or which is otherwise unsolicited. This
     information from third parties forms part of your Personal Information.
 2.6 Where the NRL receives unsolicited Personal Information about you, it will, within a
     reasonable period after receiving that information, determine whether or not it could have
     collected the information if the NRL had solicited the information itself. If the NRL
     determines that it could not have collected the Personal Information the NRL will, as soon as
     practicable but only if it is lawful and reasonable to do so, destroy the information or ensure
     that the information is de-identified.
 2.7 If the NRL collects Personal Information about you from someone other than yourself (or
     your parent or legal guardian), the NRL will take reasonable steps to ensure you are made
     aware of the matters listed in clause 2.8 below. Generally, if appropriate, the NRL will tell
     you why it is collecting Personal Information and how it plans to use it, unless it is
     impracticable to do so or it is self-evident.
 2.8 Before or at the time of collection of Personal Information (or if that is not practicable, as
     soon as practicable after), the NRL will take reasonable steps to ensure that you are aware
     of:
     (a)      how to contact the NRL in relation to this Privacy Policy;
                                                                                                    2

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
            (b)     the fact that you can gain access to the information held on you and seek correction
                    of such information;
            (c)     the purposes for which the information is collected;
            (d)     the organisations (or types of organisations) to which the NRL usually discloses
                    information of that kind;
            (e)     any law that requires the information to be collected;
            (f)     the main consequences (if any) for you if all or part of the information is not
                    provided;
            (g)     whether the NRL is likely to disclose the personal information to overseas
                    recipients; and
            (h)     if the NRL is likely to disclose your Personal Information to overseas recipients (for
                    example, to facilitate membership mail outs) — the countries in which such
                    recipients are likely to be located if it is practicable to specify those countries in the
                    notification or to otherwise make you aware of them.
   Sensitive information
   2.9      The NRL will not collect Sensitive Information about you unless:
            (a)     you have consented;
            (b)     it is specifically permitted to do so under the NRL Rules, including for health,
                    medical and anti-doping testing purposes and investigation of disputes (whatever
                    the nature of the dispute), or if it is reasonably necessary for one or more of the
                    NRL’s functions or activities in administering the game of Rugby League;
            (c)     the collection is required or authorised by law;
            (d)     a Permitted General Situation exists; or
            (e)     otherwise permitted under the provisions of the Australian Privacy Principles
                    relating to the collection of Sensitive Information.
3. USE AND DISCLOSURE
   3.1      The NRL will not use or disclose Personal Information about you for a secondary purpose
            other than the primary purposes (the secondary purpose) identified in clause 2.1 above
            unless:
            (a)     you have consented to the use or disclosure;
            (b)     both of the following apply:
                                                                                                             3

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
                  (i)      the secondary purpose is related to the primary purpose of collection and,
                           if the Personal Information is Sensitive Information, directly related to the
                           primary purpose of collection; and
                  (ii)     you would reasonably expect the NRL to use or disclose the information for
                           the secondary purpose;
         (c)      a Permitted General Situation exists.
 Direct Marketing
 3.2     The NRL may use or disclose your Personal Information to a Rugby League Administrator
         for the secondary purpose of direct marketing communication, if:
         (a)     it collected the information from you;
         (b)     you would reasonably expect your Personal Information would be used or disclosed
                 for direct marketing;
         (c)     the NRL has provided a simple means by which you can request not to receive direct
                 marketing; and
         (d)     you have not made a request of the kind referred to in 3.2(c).
 3.3     In other cases where you would not reasonably expect your Personal Information to be used
         for direct marketing, or the information has been collected from a third party, the NRL may
         use the information for the secondary purpose of direct marketing communication only if
         the following are satisfied:
         (a)      you have consented to the use or disclosure for direct marketing, or it is
                  impracticable to seek your consent before that use;
         (b)      the NRL will not charge you for giving effect to a request by you not to receive
                  direct marketing communication;
         (c)      You have not made a request to the NRL not to receive direct marketing
                  communication;
         (d)      In each direct marketing communication, the NRL always prominently displays a
                  simple notice or actionable option that you may express a wish not to receive any
                  further direct marketing communication; and
         (e)      each written direct marketing communication by the NRL with you sets out the
                  NRL’s contact details including business address, telephone and fax numbers, and
                  email address.
 3.4     The NRL may disclose your Personal Information to its service providers such as ticketing
         agents, mail houses or other similar third-party organisations for the purpose of
                                                                                                         4

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
          implementing the primary purposes, including fulfilling ticket requests and communicating
          Rugby League related offers. For example, the NRL uses third party credit card payment
          gateway services on its website. If you pay for tickets or services through the NRL’s website,
          the NRL will be required to provide certain financial details to the third party service
          provider to effect the transaction. The NRL requires these third party organisations to keep
          your contact details and Personal Information confidential and only use them for the
          designated purpose.
   3.5    Subject to compliance with the Privacy Act and this Privacy Policy, the NRL may also:
          (a)      disclose your Personal Information to its affiliates (including without limitation the
                   Leagues, a Competition Administrator and a Club) to enable them to administer the
                   game of Rugby League in their area and provide related activities and services; and
          (b)      unless you inform the NRL otherwise, disclose your information to sponsors and
                   partners to enable them to provide you with information, materials and promotional
                   opportunities.
   3.6    The NRL may, in its discretion, disclose your Personal Information where it is otherwise
          permitted or required to do so under the Australian Privacy Principles or at law.
4. DATA QUALITY AND SECURITY
   4.1    The NRL will take reasonable steps to make sure that the Personal Information it collects,
          uses or discloses is accurate, complete and up-to-date.
   4.2    The NRL will also take reasonable steps to protect the Personal Information it holds about
          you or that is within its direct control from misuse, interference and loss and from
          unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. However, the internet is an inherently risky
          environment and any information you send via digital means is sent at your own risk.
   4.3    The NRL will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify Personal
          Information if it is no longer needed for any purpose for which the information may be used
          or disclosed under clause 2, unless the NRL is required by or under an Australian law, or a
          Court order, to retain the information.
5. OPENNESS, ACCESS AND CORRECTION
   5.1    At your request, the NRL will take reasonable steps to let you know, in general terms, what
          sort of Personal Information it holds, for what purposes, and how it collects, holds, uses and
          discloses that information.
   5.2    The NRL will provide you, within a reasonable period after a request from you, with access
          to the Personal Information it holds on you, except to the extent that the NRL is not required
          to do so under Article 12.3 of the Australian Privacy Principles.
   5.3    Before supplying any Personal Information to you, the NRL must be reasonably satisfied as
          to your identity (for example, by asking to see your passport or driver’s licence). The NRL is
                                                                                                          5

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
           not under any obligation to provide Personal Information to you where the NRL is not
           required to do so under the Australian Privacy Principles or otherwise at law.
   5.4     If the NRL refuses to provide you with access to Personal information it holds on you in the
           manner requested by you or because one of the exceptions in Article 12.3 of the Australian
           Privacy Principles applies, the NRL will either:
           (a)      take such steps (if any) as are reasonable in the circumstances to give access to the
                    information in a way that meets the needs of the NRL and you; or
           (b)      provide you with a written notice that sets out:
                    (i)     the reasons for the refusal except to the extent that, having regard to the
                            grounds for the refusal, it would be unreasonable to do so; and
                    (ii)    the mechanisms available to complain about the refusal; and
                    (iii)   any other matter prescribed by the Privacy Act regulations.
   5.5     If:
           (a)      the NRL is satisfied that, having regard to a purpose for which the Personal
                    Information is held, the information is inaccurate, out-of-date, incomplete or
                    irrelevant or misleading; or
           (b)      you request the NRL to correct your Personal Information,
           the NRL will take reasonable steps to correct the Personal Information to ensure that,
           having regard to the purpose for which it is held, it is accurate, up-to-date, complete,
           relevant and not misleading. The NRL will not charge you for making such a request or for
           correcting the information.
   5.6     If the NRL refuses to correct the Personal Information at your request, the NRL will provide
           you with a written notice that sets out the same matters listed in 5.4(b).
6. NO LIABILITY
   6.1     To the maximum extent permissible by law, the NRL expressly disclaims any liability for a
           breach of this Policy.
   6.2     By providing the NRL with Personal Information, you acknowledge that any damage caused
           to you or any other individual by the disclosure of that information shall be limited to the
           amount recoverable under applicable legislation and otherwise not be recoverable from the
           NRL or any of its related bodies.
                                                                                                         6

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
7. TRANSBORDER DATA FLOWS
   7.1     The NRL will not transfer your Personal Information unless it has first taken steps
           reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the information that it transfers will not be
           held, used or disclosed by the recipient of the information inconsistently with, or otherwise
           in breach of, the Australian Privacy Principles (for example, by adopting appropriate
           contractual clauses).
   7.2     The NRL may transfer Personal Information about you to someone who is in a foreign
           country only if:
           (a)       the NRL reasonably believes that the recipient is subject to a law or binding scheme
                     that has the effect of protecting the information in a way that is, overall,
                     substantially similar to the Australian Privacy Principles and there are mechanisms
                     available to you to enforce that protection or scheme;
           (b)       you consent to the transfer after the NRL has informed you that 7.1 will no longer
                     apply if you provide your consent.
   7.3     Clause 7.1 does not apply to the transfer of Personal Information in accordance with the
           NRL Rules, including to facilitate the registration of a Player by an international Rugby
           League association.
8. INQUIRIES PROCEDURE
   8.1     All complaints and inquiries concerning your Personal Information, including in respect of
           alleged breaches of this Privacy Policy or the Australian Privacy Principles, will be directed
           to the NRL Privacy Officer (or a person who is delegated that function from time to time).
           This will ensure that all such matters will be dealt with:
           (a)       consistently across the NRL (rather than having a series of different approaches
                     across the NRL); and
           (b)       in accordance with applicable law, including the Privacy Act.
   8.2     At all times, privacy complaints will be treated seriously, dealt with promptly and
           confidentially, and will not affect your existing obligations or commercial arrangements
           with the NRL.
9. INTERPRETATION
   9.1     Any capitalised terms or phrases used but not defined in this Policy have the meaning given
           to them in the Privacy Act.
   9.2     Any reference to the NRL in this Privacy Policy is a reference to all those entities individually
           and collectively unless the context requires otherwise.
                                                                                                           7

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
     9.3        This Privacy Policy is designed to safeguard Personal Information and to comply with the
                law and so may need to be varied or changed by the NRL from time to time.
     9.4        Headings are for ease of reference only and do not affect the meaning of the parts of this
                Policy.
     9.5        The singular includes the plural and vice versa and words importing a gender include other
                genders.
     9.6        Other grammatical forms of defined words or expressions have corresponding meanings.
     9.7        A reference to a Rule or sub-Rule or to a Schedule or Guideline is a reference to a Rule or
                sub-Rule of these Rules or to a Schedule or Guideline to these Rules respectively.
     9.8        A reference to a document or agreement, including these Rules, includes a reference to that
                document or agreement as amended, novated, altered or replaced from time to time.
10. DEFINITIONS
In this Policy:
Club means any Club registered with the NRL or the Leagues from time to time. A reference to Club
includes a club admitted by:
(a)      a Competition Administrator to field a team in a Competition; or
(b)      the NRL to field a team in a NRL Competition.
Club Official means any person involved with the administration, management or organisation of a Club
(whether paid or unpaid), including employees, contractors, consultants, volunteers, officers and
directors and representatives.
Competition means any competition, tournament or league registered or carried out under the auspices
of the NRL or the Leagues including the pre-season, season proper, finals series and any post season
tournament or knockout cup competition and any other football competition or tournament organised,
hosted by or carried out under the auspices the NRL or the Leagues.
Competition Administrator means the entity responsible for the conduct and staging of a Competition
and includes (without limitation) the NRL and the Leagues (including the divisions and associations that
make up the Leagues).
Health Information means:
(a)      information or an opinion about:
         (i)      your health or a disability (at any point in time);
         (ii)     your expressed wishes about the future provision of health services to you; or
                                                                                                            8

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
         (iii)  a health service provided, or to be provided, to you, that is also Personal Information;
(b)      other Personal Information collected to provide, or in providing, a health service; or
(c)      other Personal Information about you collected in connection with the donation, or intended
         donation, by you of your body parts, organs or body substances.
Leagues means NRL, Queensland Rugby League, New South Wales Rugby League, Country Rugby League
of NSW and the States and Territories of Australia that do not currently have a Club competing in the NRL
Competition based within their territorial limits.
Match means a game of Rugby League football and includes any match staged, participated in,
sanctioned by, or played under the auspices of the NRL, the Leagues or a Competition Administrator
(including any match held as part of a Competition).
Match Official means any person in charge of safety or any other person appointed by the NRL, the
Leagues or a Competition Administrator to assume responsibility in connection with a Match including:
(a)      The referee for a Match;
(b)      The touch judges for a Match;
(c)      If used, the in-goal touch judges for a Match;
(d)      The interchange officials for a Match;
(e)      The video referee for a Match;
(f)      The sin-bin operator for a Match;
(g)      The timekeeper or timekeepers for a Match;
(h)      The ground manager for any ground where a Match is played;
(i)      Any person who assists in the preparation for, or the conduct of, a Match (including the
         organisation, management, control or administration of the Match as an event), and whether any
         such persons is:
         (i)      Engaged by the NRL or a Club or otherwise;
         (ii)     An employee, contractor, agent, volunteer or otherwise; or
         (iii)    Paid or unpaid.
National Youth Competition means the National Under 20 elite Rugby League competition arranged,
organized and administered by the NRL.
                                                                                                         9

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
NRL Privacy Officer means the person appointed by the NRL from time to time to deal with complaints
and inquiries under this Policy.
NRL Rules means its constitution, rules, regulations, policies and procedures and any other ancillary
document that governs the NRL in administering the game of Rugby League, as promulgated and
amended from time to time.
Official means:
(a)      a Club Official, Match Official or Team Official;
(b)      an employee, consultant, officer or director of the NRL, the Leagues or a Competition
         Administrator; or
(c)      a member of a council, committee, panel or body constituted by the NRL, the Leagues or a
         Competition Administrator.
Permitted General Situation exists if, in relation to the collection, use or disclosure by the NRL of
Personal Information about you:
(a)      it is unreasonable or impracticable to obtain your consent to the collection, use or disclosure;
(b)      the NRL reasonably believes that the collection, use or disclosure is necessary to lessen or
         prevent a serious threat to the life, health or safety of any individual, or to public health or
         safety;
(c)      the NRL has reason to suspect that unlawful activity, or misconduct of a serious nature, that
         relates to the NRL functions or activities has been, is being or may be engaged in (including such
         things as investigations into breaches of the NRL Rules);
(d)      the NRL reasonably believes that the collection, use or disclosure is necessary in order for the
         entity to take appropriate action in relation to the matter;
(e)      the collection, use or disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment, exercise or
         defence of a legal or equitable claim.
Personal Information means information or an opinion (including forming part of a database), whether
true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an individual whose identity is
apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion.
Player means any person who is, from time to time, registered to a Club or is selected as a member of a
Representative Team, whether that person is male or female, junior or senior or an amateur or
professional.
Privacy Act means the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).
Representative Match means a team participating in a Representative Match.
                                                                                                          10

National Rugby League
Privacy Policy
Representative Team means any team selected to participate in a Representative Match.
Rugby League Administrators mean the NRL, the Leagues, a Competition Administrator or a Club (as the
case may be) with which the Participant has a direct relationship, including for the purposes of
registration with the League and participation in a Competition.
Rugby League Partners means any entity that has a commercial agreement or arrangement with the
NRL, Member Association, Competition Administrator or Club (as the case may be) and which you may
also have a direct relationship with (including by participation in a Competition).
Sensitive Information means:
(a)      information or an opinion about your:
         (i)       racial or ethnic origin;
         (ii)      political opinions;
         (iii)     membership of a political association;
         (iv)      religious beliefs or affiliations;
         (v)       philosophical beliefs;
         (vi)      membership of a professional or trade association;
         (vii)     membership of a trade union;
         (viii)    sexual preferences or practices; or
         (ix)      criminal record, that is also Personal Information; or
(b)      Health Information.
Team Official means any personnel involved with the management, preparation or participation of a
Club’s team (whether paid or unpaid), including the coaches, managers, medical staff (including team or
match day doctor), physiotherapists, gear persons and other support staff.
                                                                                                        11
